<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FoodSpan</title>
    <description>FoodSpan is an amazing service!
</description>
    <link>https://foodspan.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://foodspan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:07:37 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:07:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>She Put Her Onion Roots in Water... You&#39;ll Never Believe What Happens Next!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt about it: food is expensive. The average Canadian household spends over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www5.statcan.gc.ca/cansim/a05?lang=eng&amp;amp;id=2030028&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$675 a month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on food, with $490 of that being store-bought food. No matter how much you try to avoid it, the supermarket often becomes your second home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if I told you there was a way to &lt;em&gt;regrow vegetables&lt;/em&gt; from the parts most people don’t find very useful, like the roots of an onion or the bottom of a head of lettuce? It’s as simple as plopping the vegetable in some water and… voilà! After a few weeks, it’ll regenerate itself and you’ll have a new yummy ingredient to cook with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to learn how to save yourself some trips to the supermarket?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;green-onions&quot;&gt;1. Green Onions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/regrow-onions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Regrow Onions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chopped onions are a culinary aesthete’s favourite garnish. They can be used to add the finishing touches to soups, omelettes, dips, potato salads, stir-fry dishes… the list goes on and on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out how to grow your own &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/vnjtI&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;garlic-sprouts&quot;&gt;2. Garlic Sprouts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/regrow-garlic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Regrow Garlic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love garlic, but want something a little milder? Try garlic sprouts! They taste great on top of baked potatoes and salads, and act as the perfect “little something” for dips such as hummus and guacamole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find directions
&lt;a href=&quot;http://simpledailyrecipes.com/8594/how-to-grow-your-own-garlic-chives/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;romaine-lettuce&quot;&gt;3. Romaine Lettuce&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/regrow-lettuce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Regrow Lettuce&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the obvious salad or wrap, lettuce can be used in a plethora of recipes! Have you ever tried roasting or stir-frying it? From smoothies to tacos, this leafy green will put a smile on your face no matter how you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lettuce&lt;/em&gt; show you how you can grow your own! Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://threepsandq.wordpress.com/2011/12/11/peculiarities-and-plants-romaine-lettuce/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link to learn how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;basil&quot;&gt;4. Basil&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/regrow-basil.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Regrow Basil&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t go wrong with basil! A quick Google search turned up countless recipes whose names alone will make your mouth water. Pasta, salads, fish… add basil to anything and &lt;em&gt;pesto&lt;/em&gt;! Every bite will taste like spring with this &lt;a href=&quot;http://foodfacts.mercola.com/basil.html&quot;&gt;superfood&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the instructions &lt;a href=&quot;http://cepsinthecity.blogspot.ca/2011/06/basil-plants-from-cuttings.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several other vegetables you can grow in a similar fashion, but the ones we chose are among the fastest and easiest to grow. Regrowing food is one way to reduce food waste… another would be using &lt;strong&gt;FoodSpan&lt;/strong&gt;! Hopefully this blog post gave you an idea of how to be more sustainable when it comes to chowing down. Until next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 17:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://foodspan.github.io/news/2016/08/08/food-that-regrows-itself.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://foodspan.github.io/news/2016/08/08/food-that-regrows-itself.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Amazing Tips and Tricks to Make Instant Noodles Healthier and Tastier!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instant Noodles&lt;/strong&gt; are the staple to any university student’s diet, and they’re dirt cheap too! That being said, you often compensate on getting healthy, nutritious food for a lower price. But that’s not cool! Here, we have &lt;strong&gt;6 amazing ways&lt;/strong&gt; that you can make your instant noodles taste good, good for you, and your wallet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;go-green-put-some-veggies-in-there&quot;&gt;1. Go Green: Put some veggies in there!!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/green-onion.png&quot; alt=&quot;Green Onions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instant Noodles is only going to get you one out of the four food groups, so get some awesome vegetables in there! They also add tons of flavour, and make your pot of noodles look pretty green! Some common vegetables for Instant Noodles include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green Onions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bean Sprouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lettuce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broccoli&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spinach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carrots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find most of these foods at your local supermarkets for a pretty cheap price: look especially for ethnic Asian supermarkets, as noodle ingredients are pretty cheap there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;noodles-can-be-eggcellent&quot;&gt;2. Noodles can be Eggcellent!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/egg-instant-noodle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eggs in Instant Noodles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eggs are often a staple for most kinds of foods, and instant noodles are no exception! You can cook them in many different ways: poached, boiled, omelette, or anything in between!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;give-your-instant-noodles-some-meat&quot;&gt;3. Give your instant noodles some meat!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/beef-instant-noodles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meat in Instant Noodles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People love meat, whether it’s in your burger, grilled food, or even your noodles! You can toss in your pork, beef, or chicken to simmer while you’re boiling your instant noodles, and it turns out amazing! Seafood works even better: shrimp, lobster, or fish doesn’t taste fishy! It tastes even better when the meat juices soak into the soup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dont-be-a-chicken-use-chicken-stock&quot;&gt;4. Don’t be a chicken, use Chicken Stock!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/chicken-instant-noodles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chicken Soup Stock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinking noodle soup is sooo tasty, especially on a cold day. But you don’t want just the flavour packet and water in there! Adding some chicken soup stock can go a long way into making both the noodles and the soup a little chicken soup for the soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-saucy&quot;&gt;5. Get Saucy!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/soy-sauces.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Soy Sauces&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love being saucy, especially with instant noodles! Soy Sauce, Sesame Oil, and Vinegar are some basic sauces you can add in; if you’re feeling adventurous, try sriracha, Tabasco, or any other hot sauces. Get saucy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;make-your-instant-noodles-butter&quot;&gt;6. Make your Instant Noodles Butter!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/butter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Butter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding Butter to your Ramen makes it taste smooooooth, just like butter. Give it a shot! If you’re looking for creamier instant noodles, add some milk in too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully now you’re able to raise the bar for your instant noodles. As a reminder, you can store all of these ingredients in your fridge, and use FoodSpan to keep track of all your ingredients and expiry dates. Have fun out there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 21:58:07 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://foodspan.github.io/news/2016/08/06/how-to-make-instant-noodles-healthy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://foodspan.github.io/news/2016/08/06/how-to-make-instant-noodles-healthy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to FoodSpan!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Leverage agile frameworks to provide a robust synopsis for high level overviews. Iterative approaches to corporate strategy foster collaborative thinking to further the overall value proposition. Organically grow the holistic world view of disruptive innovation via workplace diversity and empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring to the table win-win survival strategies to ensure proactive domination. At the end of the day, going forward, a new normal that has evolved from generation X is on the runway heading towards a streamlined cloud solution. User generated content in real-time will have multiple touchpoints for offshoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitalise on low hanging fruit to identify a ballpark value added activity to beta test. Override the digital divide with additional clickthroughs from DevOps. Nanotechnology immersion along the information highway will close the loop on focusing solely on the bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 21:07:07 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://foodspan.github.io/news/2016/08/02/welcome-to-foodspan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://foodspan.github.io/news/2016/08/02/welcome-to-foodspan.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
